Buzz Lightyear mission log.
巴斯光年任务日读
All signs point to this planet as the location of Zurg's fortress,
所有的驴象都显示 这就是杞克天王的星球
but there seems to be no sign of intelligent life anywhere.
但是名没有 智慧形生物的跑影
Come to me, my prey.
自投团网吧，我的猎物
To infinity and beyond!
飞向宇密…浩瀚扰地
So, we meet again, Buzz Lightyear, for the last time.
我们又见面了，巴斯光年 这坎你死定了
Not today, Zurg!
你休想，札克
You almost had him.
不 …-不 多 你差点就打败他
- I'm never gonna defeat Zurg! - Sure, you will, Rex.
我永这都赢不了札克 你会赢的，抱抱龙
In fact, you're a better Buzz than lam.
你当巴斯比我晃要属害
But look at my little arms!
我的手太短了
I can't press the "fire" button and jump at the same time!
我不能同时按 发射和跳趴的按键
Where is it?
在哪儿 ?
- Woody? - Huh?
胡迪
Hang on, cowboy!
列慌，牛仓
- Woody, are you all right? - Yeah.
你没事吧 ?
Yeah, I'm fine, Buzz. OK. Here's your list of things to do while I'm gone.
我没事啦，巴斯 我不在的时候别总了人这些事
Batteries need to be changed.
记得要换电池
Toys in the bottom of the chest need to be rotated.
让要底的玩具出来适透气
And make sure everyone attends Mr. Spell's seminar...
大家都要上拼字先生的课
on what to do if you or a part of you is swallowed.
[玩具被吞食该如何应变1
OK? OK. Good. OK.
好吗 ?很好
Woody, you haven't found your hat yet, have you?
你还没找到惕子，对吧 ?
And Andy's leaving for cowboy camp any minute,
对，安第要参加牛仔合
and I can't find it anywhere!
我分找不到牛仔惕
Don't worry, Woody. In just a few hours,
别担心，再遇姓个饼头
you'll be sitting around a campfire with Andy making delicious, hot "sch'moes."
你就能跟安弟坐在营火劣 一起烧香喷喷的马伶蓝
- They're called s'mores, Buzz. - Right. Right. Of course.
是著薯啦，巴斯 没错，好吧
Has anyone found Woody's hat yet?
谁找到胡迪的巾子吗 ?
Keep looking, men. Dig deeper! Negatory. Still searching.
弟兄们，继续找 报告，我们选在找
The lawn gnome next door says it's not in the yard, but he'll keep lookin’.
前院小矮人说不在院子里 但是他会继续找
It's not in Molly's room. We've looked everywhere.
我们到让都找明了
- [found it. - You found my hat?
我找到了 你找到我的惕子 ?
Your hat? No. The missus lost her earring.
你的巾子?不是啦 我老朔和琉了耳环
- My little sweet potato! - You found it!
我的亲亲和蛋头太太 你找到了
It's so nice...
家里有个
to have a big, strong spud around the house.
强大的蛋头老公真好
That's just great.
这下可好了
This'll be the first year l miss cowboy camp, all because of my stupid hat!
我去不成牛仔警 都是因久一顶功惕子
- Woody, look under your boot. - Don't be silly.
胡迪，看看你的蒜底 列傻了
- My hat is not under my boot. - Would you just look?
帽子不在那儿 你看看六
No hat. Just the word "Andy."
瞧，没有惕子 只有【上「安半」 这十个字
And the boy who wrote that
不管你有没有由子
would take you to camp with or without your hat.
他膛是会带你去牛仔营
I'm sorry, Bo.
对不起，裤中
It's just that I've been lookin’ forward to this all year.
只是我等了一整年
It's my one time with just me and Andy.
才能重独跟安弟相处
You're cute when you care.
你放样好可爱哦
- Bo, not in front of Buzz. - Let him look.
列在巴斯面前人这样蔚 管他的，他壹看就看
Miss Peep, your sheep!
实具小姐，的绵羊
This is Al from Al's Toy Barn,
我是艾震玩具城的艾震
and I'm sittin’ on good deals.
这儿有便宜货
think I'm feeling a deal hatching right now.
好东西正要破卵而出
Let's see what we got. We got boats for a buck, Beanies for a buck...
让我看看有什么 我有一掀仅的玩具船、豆娃娃
- Turn it off! Someone's gonna hear! - Which one is off?
快天掉，有人会匠到 怎广明呀?
Buck-buck-buck! And that's cheap-cheap-cheap! So hurry on down...
价弘低得咕咕叫
For cryin’ out loud, it's this one.
是这个按鳃
- [despise that chicken. - Fellas! Fellas!
大影儿
OK, I got some good news, and I got some bad news.
我有好消息跟雯消息
What news?
快襄吧 什么消息?
The good news is I found your hat, Woody.
好消息是我找到你的惕子
My hat! Slink, thank you. Thank you, thank you, thank you.
我的蝎子 弹筑狗，谢谢你…
- Where'd you find it? - Well, that's the bad news.
你在哪儿找到的? 这就是雯消息
It's Buster!
是小狗巴斯特
Canine alert! Man your battle stations!
恶犬来式 ! 全面备战 !
Let's move, move, move!
快行动 !
Woody! Hide! Quick!
胡迪，快躲起来
OK, OK, OK. OK, OK! You found me!
好啦…好啦…你找到我了
Buster, all right. Hey, how did he do, Hamm?
角了，巴斯特 火腿，邱的表现如何?
- Looks like a new record. - OK, boy. Sit.
季又天新纪尔 乖，狗狗，坐下
Reach for the sky.
把手举起来
Gotcha!
你死了
Great job, boy.
好棒哦，狗狗
Who's gonna miss me while I'm gone, huh?
我走了谁会想我 ?
Who's gonna miss me?
谁会想我 ?
Andy, you got all your stuff?
安弟，你的倒子呢 ?
Have a good weekend, everybody. I'll see you Sunday night.
大采儿过末恰快 礼拜天见
It's in my room.
在我的房间
Stick 'em up.
手光起来
I guess we'll work on that later.
我改天再教你吧
Hey, Woody. Ready to go to cowboy camp?
胡迪，淮人备去牛仔悟唾
Andy, honey, come on. Five minutes, and we're leavin’.
安弟，快点，五分甸和后出发
Five minutes.
五分甸
Help, help! Somebody help me!
救命啊 ! 谁来救我?
Let her go, evil Dr. Pork Chop!
那恶的和猪排博士，放开她
Never!
不行
You must choose, Sheriff Woody. How shall she die?
你得选择，胡迪警长 你要她怎广死 ?
Shark, or death by monkeys?
苟鳃?还是被猴子吃掉?
Choose!
快选择吧
I choose Buzz Lightyear!
我还择巴斯光年
What? That's not a choice!
那可不行
To infinity and beyond!
飞向宇密…浩瀚扰地
- I'll save you, Miss Peep. - My hero.
我来救妹，实上贝小姐 我的大英雄
- Thanks, Buzz. - No problem, buddy.
府了，巴斯 不客气，兄弟
You should never tangle with the unstoppable duo
千蓝列车上所向把淫的…
of Woody and Buzz Lightyear!
…胡迪和巴斯光年
Oh, no.
烧了
Andy, let's go! Molly's already in her car seat.
安弟，走了，妹妹都上车了
- But, Mom, Woody's arm ripped. - Oh, no.
妈味，胡迪的手被扯破了
- Maybe we can fix him on the way. - No, just leave him.
也许可以在路上补好 不要，列带去吧
I'm sorry, honey, but you know toys don't last forever.
别交遇，乎乖 玩具没有永吉不壕的
- What happened? - Woody's been shelved.
怎广回事 ? 胡迪被放到架子上
Andy!
安第
- Woody? - Woody? Honey, are you OK?
胡迪 ? 胡迪，钙哥，你还好吧 ?
Ride 'em, cowboy!
哼呀，快骑吧，牛仓
He's back? Hey, everybody! Andy's back! He's back early from cowboy camp!
他回来了? 他回来了 安弟从牛仔营提早回来了
Places, everybody! Andy's coming!
各就各位，安弟求了
Hey, Woody! Did you miss me?
胡迪，你想我吗 ?
Giddyap, giddyap, giddyap. Ride 'em, cowboy!
快瑚吧，牛仔
I forgot. You're broken.
我各了，你雯了
I don't wanna play with you anymore.
我不要跟你玩了
No, Andy! No. No, Andy! No!
不，安第，不!
Andy. Andy.
安弟，安第
Bye, Woody.
永别了，胡迪
No! No! Andy!
安弟，列走 !
Wheezy, is that you?
咏咳，是你吗 ?
- Hey, Woody. - What are you doing up here?
，胡迪 你怎订会在这儿 ?
I thought Mom took you to get your squeaker fixed months ago.
我以禹嫣味 老早就把你修好了
- Andy was so upset. - Nah.
安和弟很著急耶 没有
She just told him that to calm him down
她只是安奈安弟而已
and then put me on the shelf.
然后就把我放上来
- Why didn't you yell for help? - Well, I tried squeakin'.
你怎廊不求救呢 ? 我试著咏咏叫
But I'm still broken. No one could hear me.
可是没有用，没有人匠得到
Besides, the dust aggravates my condition.
沈且灰订让我病得更重
What's the point in prolonging the inevitable?
反正我是无药可救了
We're all just one stitch away from here to there.
我们最后都会渝落到那儿的
Yard sale? Yard sale!
前院拍喜
Yard sale! Guys, wake up, wake up! There's a yard sale outside!
前院拍责 ! 大彩儿，醒醒 外面在拍喜
- Yard sale? - Sarge, emergency roll call!
前院拍喜 ? 队长，紧急加名
Sir, yes, sir! Red alert!
是，长官 紧急状况
All civilians fall in position now! Single file! Let's move, move, move!
马上全体集合 排成一列，快点
- Hamm? - Here.
火腿
- Potato Head, Mr. and Mrs.?
蛋头先生、太大 在
Troikas. Check, check, check, check, check.
蛋包蛋，在在在在在
l hate yard sales!
我最讨习大拍喜
Someone's coming!
有人来了
OK. Let's see what's up here.
好吧，让我看看有什么 (雨毛五)
Bye, Woody.
永别了，胡迪
Wheezy! Think, think, Woody. Think, think, think.
号号 快点，胡迪，快想办法
Hey. Here, boy. Here, Buster!
狗狗，我在上面
OK, boy. To the yard sale!
好了，快到前院
What's goin’ on? He's nuts.
怎广回事 ? 他天运了
His arm ain't that bad.
他的手没那广糟嘛
Don't do it, Woody! We love you!
列去找死，我们爱你
Careful on the steps, now.
下楼梯小心题
OK, boy. Let's go. And keep it casual.
走吧，狗狗 要装得若拓其事
Not that casual.
不是装腔作势啦
Piggy bank coming through, coming through.
火腿大答来也
- ls he out there? - There he is.
他在外面吗? 他在那儿
He's in the box!
他爬进箱子了
He's sellin’ himself for 25 cents!
他只把自己标价丁毛五
You're worth more than that.
胡迪，你没这广不值袋吧
Hold on. Hold on. He's got something.
等等，他找到什么
- It's Wheezy! - Wheezy?
是咳叶 号叶?
Hey, it's not suicide. It's a rescue.
他不是自杀，他是去救人
Good boy, Buster. Hold still. There. There you go, pal.
乖狗狗，列乱动 来吧，好兄弟
- Bless you, Woody. - All right, now.
你真好，胡地 好了
Back to Andy's room.
回安第房间吧
Way to go, cowboy.
干得好，牛仔
- Golly bob howdy! - Woody, I'm slipping!
真是了不起 胡迪，我快掉下去了
Mommy... Mommy, look! Look at this!
妈味，人看看
- Mommy, look! It's a cowboy dolly! - Hey, that's not her toy!
人看，是一个牛仔娃娃 胡迪不是她的玩具
What's that little gal think she's doin'?
那个小女孩想干癖?
Mommy, Mommy, can we get it? Please? Mommy, please?
妈味，圈啦，好不好?
You don't want that toy. It's broken.
乖冬，不要啦，它玉了
There's a snake in my boot.
我的就子里有蛇
Original hand-painted face. Natural-dyed, blanket-stitched vest!
原版手工上漆 天然染色、镇遵背心
Little rip. Fixable. If only you had your hand-stitched, polyvinyl...
有点破，能补救 希望有你的手儿尼郁布负…
A hat! I found him! I found him! I found him!
…牛仔幅 我找到了，我找到了
Buster! Quiet down!
巴斯特，安才
- Excuse me. Can I help you? - Yes.
抱娄，我能帮忙吗 ? 当然能
You can help take his paws off my pal.
叫他别碰我的好友
I'll give you 50 cents for all this junk.
我出五毛纱圈这个破玩具
- Now, how did this get down here? - Hand her the sheriff.
这怎订会在这儿 ? 乖乖的把警长…
Nice and easy.
…交给好
- Five dollars. - I'm sorry. It's an old family toy.
五泥级 抱娄，这是家和里的玩具
Now just walk away.
乎冬给我走并
- Wait. - The other way.
另外一尊
- I'll give you 50 bucks for him. - Fifty bucks ain't bad.
我出五十淘绥 五十元不少炙耶
- It's not for sale. - Everything's for sale.
我不误 什么都能买过或交易
- Or trade. You like my watch? - Sorry.
喜欢我的镇吗 ? 抱攻
- He's safe. Way to go! - She showed him!
他得救了，安弟的妈咪菌茂 棒呆了，她让他吃瘤
- Molly, don't touch that, sweetie. - Yeah. Go home, Mr. Fancy Car.
茉莉，列刀摸 渡回家吧，胖子
- Hold on. - What's up?
等等 什么事 ?
What is it, Buzz?
巴斯，怎广了?
What's happening?
发生什么事 ?
What's he doing?
他在干咏 ?
I can't watch! Can someone cover my eyes?
我不敢看 虑住我的眼睛，好吗 ?
- He's stealin' Woody! - What? He can't take Woody.
他想要偷走胡迪 什么 ?
It's illegal.
那是犯法的
- Where's he going? - Do something.
他去哪儿 ?
Buzz!
巴斯
Get him, Buzz.
巴斯，阻止他
Where's the red jacket?
红色夹克在哪里?
Why would someone steal Woody?
怎广会有人要偷走胡迪呢 ?
All right. Let's review this one more time.
我们再回顾一次
At precisely 8:32-ish,
8时32分霸右
Exhibit A, Woody, was kidnapped.
证物A胡迪章到绑如
Exhibit B, a composite sketch of the kidnapper.
证物B几菲的素描
- He didn't have a beard like that. - Fine. Etch, give him a shave.
他的盘子没那广长 好吧，囊板，提他吉明子
The kidnapper was bigger than that.
绑匪比较胖
- Picky, picky, picky. - Let's just go straight to Exhibit F.
你们真挑剔 直接跳到证物F
The kidnapper's vehicle.
绑匪的车子
Now, the vehicle fled the scene in this direction.
他从这方向逃克现场
Your eyes are in backwards. It went the other way.
你的眼睛装反了 是另一冰啦
Hey. Put a cork in it.
列教训我，和猪头
- How do you spell FBI? - My crime scene!
FBI英文怎广拼呀 ? 我的犯罪现场
Why don't you watch where you're going, Godspilla?
瞎限龙，走路要看路，好吐?
- didn't know there was a crime scene. - Excuse me. Excuse me.
我没看到犯罪现场 不好意思
A little quiet, please. Thank you.
谢谢
Lazy toy brain.
粘叶头
- Lousy try, Brian. - What are you doing, Buzz?
冰角色 巴斯，你在干咏 ?
It's some sort of message encoded on that vehicle's I.D. tag.
那辆车的车牌暗藏玄机
- Liz try bran. - It's just a license plate.
车牌的字母没什么意义
- It's just a jumble of letters. - Yeah, and there are about
没错，本郡狗共有
3.5 million registered cars in the tri-county area alone.
三百五十万辆汽车
Lou's thigh burn.
没用的软脚纯
This can't help. Let's leave Buzz to play with his toys.
没有用啦 让巴斯继续玩玩具吧
Toy. Toy. Toy. Hold on!
玩具…等等 !
- Al's Toy Barn. - Al's Toy Barn!
艾霄玩具城 艾霄玩具城!
Etch, draw that man in a chicken suit.
书板，囊出扮成公共的人
It's the chicken man!
就是那个公难人
I knew there was something I didn't like about that chicken.
我早就知道那焦难有问题
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I'll be right there.
好啦，我马上求
And we're gonna do this commercial in one take, do you hear me,
这妇广告要一次搞定
because I am in the middle of something really important.
因为我正在办一件正事
You, my little cowboy friend, are gonna make me big buck-buck-bucks.
我的小牛仔朋友 你会让我发大财…
Andy!
安第
I can't believe I have to drive all the way to work on a Saturday.
我不敢相信 他们礼拜六竟然…
All the way to work!
…要我大老下并车跑去上班
What?
什么 ?
Hey! Stop! Horsy, stop! Stop! Sit, boy!
停 ! 马儿，停! 坐下来 !
Stop it! Sit, I said!
我叫你坐 !
It's you! It's you! It's you! It's you! It's you!
是你…是你…是你…
- It's really you! - What's me?
真的是你 ! 是我
There's a snake in my boot.
我的就子里有蛇
- It is you! - Please stop saying that.
就是你 请你别再说了
Prospector said someday you'd come.
老矿工就说有一天你会来
Sweet mother of Abraham Lincoln!
乖乖老天营
The Prospector! He'll wanna meet ya!
老矿工一定很想见你
Say "hello" to the Prospector!
遇来跟老矿工问好
Never been opened.
没有拆封遇
Turn me around, Bullseye, so I can see.
红心，把我转通来
Why, the prodigal son has returned.
浪子终藉回头了
It's you! It's you!
是你，你来了
You're here! It's you!
是你…是你…
OK. I'm officially freaked-out now.
我真的被嘛雯了
We've waited countless years for this day.
我们等了多少年 才等到这一天
- It's good to see you, Woody. - Listen. I don't know wh...
很高必见到你，胡巡 了匠好，我不知道…
- Hey, how do you know my name? - Everyone knows your name, Wood-y.
你怎订知道我的名字 ? 你的名字家喻户晓，胡迪
Why, you don't know who you are, do you? Bullseye?
你不记得自己是谁吗 ? 红心
That's me.
那是我耶
Wow.
哇塞
Holy cow.
老天租
Cowboy Crunchies,
牛仓牌玉米脆片
the cereal that's sugar-frosted and dipped in chocolate,
唯一的巧克力口味上毅类早餐
proudly presents:
热情质助
Woody's Roundup Come on, it's time to play
胡迪牛仔秀，大家一起玩
There's Jessie the yodeling cowgirl
那是浴尹，唱歌女牛仔
Look it! That's me!
瞧，那是我
- Bullseye, he's Woody's horse - He's a smart one
红心，胡迪的好马儿 他真鸡明
- Pete the old Prospector - Has anyone seen my pick?
遵过矿工彼得 我的丁字键呢?
And the man himself Of course, it's time for Sheriff Woody
当然还有男主角他本人
He's the very best
胡迪整长他最行
He's the rootin'’-est tootin’-est cowboy
他是西部
In the wild, wild west
最棒最酷最炫的鳌长
Woody's Roundup
胡迪牛仔秀
I can't find it! It doesn't seem to be on any of these stations.
我找不到 每一台都找不到
- Keep looking. - You're going too slow.
继续找 你塌得太慢了
It's too fast.
太快了
- How can you even tell what's on? - l can tell.
你怎订看得到 ? 我看得到
Stop! Back, back, back!
夸回去 回去
Too late. I'm in the 40s. Got to go ‘round the horn. It's faster.
太晚了，圭头了 我要从头开始
- Back, back! Stop! - And look for the giant chicken!
对了 找到大公约就没错
Now, Etch!
书板，快忆吧
That's where I need to go.
我一定要去这壬
You can't go, Buzz. You'll never make it there.
不行，巴斯，你办不到的
Woody once risked his life to save me.
上灵胡迪冒险救我
I couldn't call myself his friend if l weren't willing to do the same.
这次我不去救他 就不配沉他的朋友
So who's with me?
谁要跟来?
I'm packing you an extra pair of shoes and your angry eyes just in case.
我替你多装一侯鞋 还有愤怒的人双眼，以防蕊一
This is for Woody when you find him.
我要你找到胡迪 赫我亲人他一下
All right,
好吧，可是我亲他
but I don't think it'll mean the same coming from me.
跟杂他的意义很不同
Mr. Buzz Lightyear, you just gotta save my pal Woody.
巴斯光年先生 你一定要把胡迪救出来
I'll do my best, son.
我会避力而积，咏叶
OK, fellas. Let's roll.
好了，大彩儿，出发吧
Geronimo!
我跳了
You'd think with all my video game experience,
我有这广多打志玩的经验
I'd be feeling more prepared.
所以应该是郊不合我
The idea is to let go.
重点是…你得放手
We'll be back before Andy gets home.
我们会赶在安弟之前回来
Don't talk to any toy you don't know!
列随便跟陌生玩具说话
To Al's Toy Barn and beyond!
飞向区霄玩具城
They don't calf this
老矿工
the old abandoned mine for nothin’, Prospector.
人记座魔球责坑真是可怕
! reckon we oughta get outta here.
我们最好赶紧出去
Where's my gold? Hold on. I'll light me a candle.
我的黄金呢? 等等，我来点几烛
Blast us to smithereens! That there's dynamite!
这是炸药，我们完蛋了
- Holy tarnation! - I'l call for help.
我的是呀
Hey, critters, go get Sheriff Woody. Now scurry!
小动物，去找胡迪警长 快去
Good job, Bullseye.
真好，红心
! reckon the new schoolhouse is finally done.
新的学校终於黄好了
What's that?
什么 ?
Jessie and Prospector are trapped in the old abandoned mine,
翌多和老矿工 被困在魔泰太闹
and Prospector just lit a stick of dynamite thinkin’ it was a candle,
老态工误触炸药
and now they're about to be blown to smithereens?
他们就快要被炸成碎片 ?
Ride like the wind, Bullseye!
和红心，快马加鞠吧
You're fannin' the flames, Jessie! It takes brains to put out that fire.
列刀风点火，翌繁 你得用头脑才能熄减炸药
My biscuits are burnin'!
我的尾股著火了
Will Woody and Bullseye land to safety?
胡迪趴红心能趴通大峡谷吗 ?
Can they reach Jessie and Stinky Pete in time?
他们能及时救出 以多跟老矿工彼得吗 ?
Tune in next week for the exciting conclusion: "Woody's Finest Hour."
下过同一时间记得收看 「 胡迪冒险记」 大结局
All right! All right! Next tape!
棒呆了，下一集
Hey, wait. What happened? What happens next?
等等，接下来怎广样 ?
- Come on! Let's see the next episode! - That's it.
我要看大结局 没有了
What?
什么 ?
The show was canceled after that.
和后来节目被迫停播
Wait, wait, wait. What about the gold mine
慢闭，那座订泰矿坑
and the cute little critters and the dynamite?
可爱的小动物跟炸药呢?
That was a great show! I mean, why cancel it?
这广精采的节目 怎广会被停播呢 ?
Two words: Sput-nik.
三个字 : 太空人
Once the astronauts went up, children only wanted to play with space toys.
太空人一登陆月球 小孩子只想玩太空玩具
l know how that feels. But still, my own show.
我知道那种感党 我有自己的节目耶
- mean, look at all this stuff! - Didn't you know?
你们看看这些玩意 你不知道吗 ?
Why, you're valuable property!
你是热门的抢手货耶
I wish the guys could see this. Hey-howdy-hey. That's me.
真希望我的朋友们能来分享 哇塞，是我耶
I'm on a yo-yo.
我有溜溜球
Nice teeth. And yet, still a good-lookin' guy.
洛和白的牙辫 钙气依然不减
It's a bank! Cool.
这是存仅简，酷吏了
What do you do? You push the hat, and out co...
这是什么 ? 只要按一下
Out come bubbles. Clever.
就会吹泡泡，真高明
Wow. What's this thing do?
这玩意是做什么的?
I get it.
我懂了
"There's a snake in my boot."
我的就子里有蛇
Hey, Bullseye. Go long! Go long!
红心，向前跑
A record player!
一台老唱机
l haven't seen one of these in ages.
我好扩没看到这个了
OK, now. Slow.
好了，现在慢一点
That's funny, Bullseye.
好好笑哦，红心
Hop on, cowgirl! Think fast!
上来吧，女牛仔 快一点
- Not bad. - It's time for Woody's Roundup
不错 胡迪牛仔秀，大家一起玩
He's the very best
他是西部
He's the rootin'’-est tootin’-est cowboy...
最棒最酷最炫的鳌长
Look at us! We're a complete set!
你看，我们浅成一整组了
- Now it's on to the museum. - Museum?
现在可以去博物馆了 博物馆 ?
- What museum? - The museum.
什么博物馆 ? 独一乱二的博物馆
We're being sold to the Konishi Toy Museum in Tokyo.
我们被过到东京的 小西玩具博物馆
- That's in Japan! - Japan?
在日本耶 日本 ?
No, no, no, no, no. I can't go to Japan.
不行，我不能去日本
What do you mean?
什么意思 ?
I've got to get back home to my owner, Andy.
我得回去找我的主人安半
Hey, look, look. See?
你们看
- He still has an owner. - My goodness.
他还有主人 我的老天
No. Can't go.
我…不要
I can't do storage again. I just can't!
我不要回去储藏室
- Jessie. - [won't go back in the dark!
翌多 我不要回到黑暗中
What's the matter? What's wrong with her?
她是怎广了 ?
Well, we've been in storage for a long time
我们一直被关在钳藏室
waiting for you.
等你来
- Why me? - The museum's
为什么 ? 一定要有你
only interested in the collection if you're in it, Woody.
博物馆才和收藏我们
Without you, we go back into storage.
没有你，我们就得回储藏室
- It's that simple. - It's not fair!
就这广简量 不公平
How can you do this to us?
你怎麻可以这样 ?
Hey, look. I'm sorry, but this is all a big mistake.
对不起，这是个错误
- You see, I was in this yard sale... - Yard sale?
我在前院拍献时被… 前院拍喜 ?
Why were you in a yard sale if you have an owner?
如果你有主人 怎广会被拍喜 ?
Well, l wasn't supposed to be there. I was trying to save another toy when...
我只是去救一个朋友
Was it because you're damaged? Did this Andy break you?
是因为你壤了吗 ? 安弟把你再壤了吐?
Yeah, but... No, no, no, no, no! It was... It was an accident.
对，但是…不对 ! 那只是个意外
- [ mean... - Sounds like he reaily loves you.
职起来他真是爱惜你
It's not like that, OK? And I'm not going to any museum!
才不是这样 我也不想去博物馆
Well, I'm not going back into storage!
我也不想回储藏室
Al's coming!
艾霄回来了
Go! Go on, Jessie.
翌儿，跳进去
Jessie, look at me.
虱缘，看著我
I promise you'll come out of the box. Now go! Go!
我保证你一定出得来 快跳进去吧
It's show time!
好矿和登场了
Money, baby. Money, money, money.
钞来也…角来也…
And now, the main attraction.
现在脸到男主角有登场
No! His arm! Where's his arm?
不 ! 他的手呢?
What am I gonna do? I know. I know.
我该怎广办 ? 我知道了
- Hello? - It's me. It's Al.
是我艾霄
I got an emergency.
我有紧急状况
- I'm busy. - Yes, we're all busy.
我在忙 大家都在忙
Look. It has to be tonight.
你今晚一定要遇来
All right. All right. But first thing in the morning.
好吧，了明天一大早就来
It's gone! I can't believe it!
完了，天啊 我不敢相信
- My arm is completely gone! - All right. Come here. Let me see that.
我的手断了
It's just a popped seam, easily repaired.
只是缚断了，很容易补的
- You should consider yourself lucky. - Lucky?
算你走运 走运 ?
Are you shrink-wrapped? lam missing my arm!
你是老糊涂吗 ? 我的手断了耶
Big deal.
那又怎样 ?
Let him go. I'm sure his precious Andy
让他走吧，他的主人这广好
is dying to play with a one-armed cowboy doll.
一定很想跟一个 独臂牛仔玩的
Why, Jessie, you know he wouldn't last an hour on the streets in his condition.
翌儿，知道他这种情况 在外头撑不了一小时
It's a dangerous world out there for a toy.
外面的世界对玩具而言 太危险了
All right. Nobody look till 1 get my cork back in.
在我塞好之前别偷看
Good work, men. Two blocks down and only 19 more to go.
干得好，走了雨休街 剩下十九条街
- What? - Nineteen?
什么 ? 十九条街 ?
Are we gonna do this all night? My parts are killing me.
还要多和久啊?我快累欧了
Come on, fellas.
列这柑
Did Woody give up when Sid had me strapped to a rocket?
我被小薛抓走胡迪有放秦吗 ? 没有
And did he give up when you threw him out of the back of that moving van?
没错，你把他踊下卡车 他有放雍哮?
- You had to bring that up. - No, he didn't!
你非得提这楼事吗 ? 他没有放秦
We have a friend in need, and we will not rest until he's safe in Andy's room!
有一个朋友需要我们 我们一定要把他安全救回家
Now let's move out!
继续前进
And that concludes our broadcast day.
今天的节目全部播放完蛙
Bullseye. Bullseye, go, go, go, go.
红心，走并
Come on. You don't wanna help me. I'm the bad guy.
列划我的忙 我是款人，记得吗?
You're gonna go back in storage because of me, remember? Just go.
我会害你们被收起来 快走开
Bullseye... All right. All right.
好啦，好啦
But you have got to keep quiet. Come on.
但是你不能出声 来吧
Over here. Attaboy.
来，好马儿
OK, Bullseye. Upsy-daisy.
好了，把我抬起来
Bullseye. Cut it out.
红心，别筷来
Stop it. Stop it, Bullseye. Stop it. Stop it.
列这檬，红心
Woody's Roundup Come on, it's time to play
胡迪牛仔秀，大家一起玩
No, Officer! 1 swear. What?
警察先生，我发的我没有…-
Get in there. There you go. Cheap case.
进去吧，好了 烟盒子
Where is the remote?
电视迁控器呢? 选控器呢?
Why don't! put it in the same place every... Here it is.
我每坎都筷放…在这儿
What is your problem?
你太卑部了
Look, I'm sorry I can't help you guys out.
很抱娄我旭不了人
Really, lam. But you didn't have to go and pull a stunt like that.
不过也不必要这一招
What? You think did that?
你说是我干的
Right. The TV just happened to turn on,
是啊，准道电视会自动打开
and the remote magically ended up in front of you!
多控器会自己 秋到面前吗 ?
- You calling me a liar? - Well, if the boot fits...
你是说我是验子吐? 娩是不打自招
Say that again.
再说一次
OK, cowboy.
好吧，牛仔
How do you like that? Take it back! Take it back!
吵到苦头了吧 把话收国去，收回去
Don't think just ‘cause you're a girl, I'm gonna take it easy on you.
列以贺你是女孩子 我就会能明你
Jessie, Woody, you stop this at once.
翌儿、胡迪，马上住手
I don't know how that television turned on,
我不知道电视怎广会打开
but fighting about it isn't helping anything.
不遇打架没有用
- If lhad both my arms... - The fact is, you don't, Woody,
要是我的双手健全… 你没有人能手
so I suggest you just wait until morning.
所以你最好等到早上
- The cleaner will come, fix your arm... - And then I'm outta here!
工匠会来修补你 然后我就走人
Oh, no, no. Bullseye, don't take it that way.
红心，你不要这样
- It's just that Andy... - Andy, Andy, Andy.
只是安弟… 安弟…安第…
That's all he ever talks about.
他只关心安第
Hey, Buzz, can we slow down?
巴斯，慢一点好吗 ?
May I remind you that some of us are carrying over six dollars in change?
我要提醒你 我可是身怀伍款耶
Losing health units. Must rest.
和能量减低，人必须休息
- ls everyone present and accounted for? - Not quite everyone.
大家都到谊了吗 ? 还没有
- Who's behind? - Mine.
谁落后了? 我的屁股
Hey, guys. Why do the toys cross the road?
大影儿 玩具高什么要通马路 ?
- Not now, Hamm. - Llove riddles. Why?
火腿，列天了 我最爱猜亦，为什么 ?
To get to the chicken on the other side!
为了到对面的公共城
The chicken!
是那焦公蕉
- Oh, well. We tried. - We'll have to cross.
我们已经吉了力 我们一定要通马路
What the...
什么 ?
You're not turning me into a mashed potato.
我可不想释成洋芋泥
I may not be a smart dog, but I know what roadkill is.
我路然不隐明 但是我知道马路如虎口
There must be a safe way.
一定有安全的办法
OK. Here's our chance. Ready. Set. Go.
机会来了 预和人，走吧
Drop!
停!
Go!
走
Drop! I said "drop"!
停 ! 我说停 !
Drop.
停
Go.
走
That went well.
挺顺利的世
Good job, troops. We're that much closer to Woody.
大彩儿，干得好 就快找到胡迪了
Thank goodness you're here.
谢天诗地，你终人於来了
Is the specimen ready for cleaning?
这和里有玩具要修理吗 ?
So how long is this gonna take?
你要花多久了时间 ?
You can't rush art.
这是艺术，和急不得
Oh, no. It's closed.
糟糙，体息了
We're not preschool toys, Slinky. We can read.
我又不是学载前玩具
Hey, Joe, you're late.
你膛到了
We've got a ton of toys to unload.
快工作吧
All right. All right. I'm comin’. I'm comin’.
好啦，我来了啦
All right. Let's go.
好了，走吧
But the sign says it's closed.
可是上面写“休息了”好
No, no, no, no. All together. Now!
等等，一起来，束!
Whoa, Nelly! How are we going to find Woody in this place?
我的妈 地方这广大怎订找呀?
Look for Al. We find Al, we find Woody. Now move out!
只要找到艾震，就能找到胡迪 出发
- Woody? - Woody.
胡迪…
There you go.
好了
He's for display only.
他是展示品
You handle him too much, he's not gonna last.
一直玩的话就会壤掉
It's amazing. You're a genius. He's just like new.
不可思议，你是个天才 他就像全新的
Wow.
哇塞
I could use one of those.
这玩意我倒是用得上
You know, they make it so you can't defeat Zurg unless you buy this book.
一定要买这本首 才能打败杞克
It's extortion. That's what it is.
这简直是敲许嘛
Hey, I always thought the golden sector was the only...
我以篇黄金宰杖是用来…
I thought we could search in style.
这样找起来比较拉风
Nice going there, Hamm. So how about letting a toy with fingers drive?
干得好，火腿 你没有手指，我来并车
Am I really that fat?
我真的有这广胖吗 ?
- What are you doing? - You're in direct violation
你在干六?
of Code 6404.5,
你这反了6404.5人条规
stating all space rangers are to be in hyper-sleep
太空战丈一定要留在瞧眠舱
until awakened by authorized personnel.
等待上级的指令
Oh, no.
不是吧
You're breakin’ ranks, ranger.
你这是有队行动
Buzz Lightyear to Star Command.
巴斯光年呼叫星际总部
- I've got an AWOL space ranger. - Tell me I wasn't this deluded.
这儿有一名逃兵 我以前没这广神经吧?
No back talk! l have a laser, and I will use it.
不准顶嘴，我有雷射光 列副我使用它
You mean the laser that's a light bulb?
什么雷射，它只是灯泡
Has your mind been melded? You could've killed me, space ranger.
你是脑袋有问题吗 ? 你差点把我害死
Or should I say "traitor"?
你这个星际叛徒
- [don't have time for this. - Halt!
我没时间跟你窜蘑共
l order you to halt!
我命令你站住
Listen to me. Listen. Wait.
职我说，双好
- We've been down this aisle already. - We've never been down this aisle.
这人条通道走遇了 才没有
- It's pink. - Face it. We're lost.
这排是粉红色的 我们迷路了
Back it up. Back it up.
退和后，退和后
What a great party!
好棒的派对
How low can you go?
你能艾多低?人能艾多低?
Excuse me, ladies.
美女们
Does anyone know where we might find the Al of Al's Toy Barn?
人们知道艾霄在哪儿吗?
I can help.
我来帮忙
I'm Tour Guide Barbie.
我是导那芭比
Please keep your hands, arms and accessories inside the car,
请别把头手和配件伸出车外
and no flash photography.
请列用闪光煤
-Thank you. -I'm a married spud. I'm a married spud.
谢谢 我是有妇之夫…
- I'ma married spud. - Then make room for the single fellas.
那就把机会让给单身汉
To our right is the Hot Wheels aisle. Developed in 1967,
右手焉是模型汽车系列 1967年系列有16琐车
the original series had 16 cars, including the Corvette.
包括雪佛苦跑车
l beg your pardon, ma'am, but where's Al's office?
对不起，小姐，请问 艾霄的办公室在哪儿 ?
Please hold all questions until the end of the tour. Thank you.
请在半览之后再发问 感洽您
It says how you defeat Zurg! Look!
上面教你怎广打败札克天王
- Excuse me, sir. - Get this outta here, "geek-osaur."
抱抱龙，快拿开
- Look out! - Stop, stop, stop!
小心了 停车 ! 停车 !
Turn into the spin, Barbie!
方向盘打直
My source of power!
我的必腾秘笈
No! Come back! Hey!
回来 !
Wait up! Hey! Come on! Slow down!
等等我，慢一点
Dinosaur overboard! Slow down!
恐龙在后面，慢一点
Remain seated, please.
请留在座位上
Listen to me. Listen to me. You're not really a space ranger.
职我说，你不是太空战警
You're a toy. We're all toys. Do you hear me?
你是个玩具 我们都是玩具
Well, that should hold you till the court martial.
你等著受军法审判吧
Let me go! You don't realize what you're doing!
放并我，你搞不懂状况
And this is the Buzz Lightyear aisle.
这和里是巴斯光年区
In 1995, shortsighted retailers did not order enough dolls to meet demand.
1995那年 巴斯光年玩偶供不应求
- Hey, Buzz! - Halt! Who goes there?
巴斯 停车，你们是谁?
Quit clownin' around and get in the car!
列关了，上车吧
Buzz, Buzz, I know how to defeat Zurg!
巴斯 我知道该怎广草败札克
- You do? - Come on. I'll tell you on the way.
真的吗 ? 上车后我再告诉你
No, no, guys! You've got the wrong Buzz! You've got the wrong Buzz!
大采儿，他不是真的巴斯 你们认错人了
Say, where'd you get the cool belt, Buzz?
这广酷的皮带哪来的?
Well, slotted pig, they're standard issue.
和猪瓜满，这是标准配备
It's like printing my own money.
我就像在印钞票一样
Yeah? What?
喂，干交?
Mr. Konishi. Yes, I have the pictures right here.
小西先生，是的 照片都在这儿
In fact, I'm in the car right now on my way to the office to fax them to you.
我正开车超去办公室 准备传真给你
I'm going through a tunnel! I'm breakin’ up!
我在遇隧道，讯号不清楚
Wow! Will you look at me? It's like I'm fresh out of the box!
你们看，我真是焕然一新
Look at this stitching! Andy's gonna have a hard time rippin’ this! Hello!
他缝得好补 这下安弟一定扯不壤
Hi! Hello!
，你好
Great. Now you can go.
太好了，你可以走了
Well, what a good idea.
真是个好主意
Woody, don't be mad at Jessie.
胡迪，列生旱尹的气
She's been through more than you know.
她受的苦也锡多了
Why not make amends before you leave, huh?
你在走之前焉她和好吧
It's the least you can do.
这是你应该做的
All right. But I don't know what good it'll do.
好吧，不过没什么用
Hey. Whatcha doin' way up here?
你在上面干嘛?
Thought I'd get one last look at the sun before I get packed away again.
我想再看太隔一腿 然后就会永下被关起来
Look, Jessie. I know you hate me for leaving,
我知道你很恨我
but I have to go back.
但是我一定要回家
I'm still Andy's toy.
我还是安弟的玩具
Well, if you knew him, you'd understand. Andy's a real...
一定会了解…
Let me guess. Andy's a real special kid.
让我猜，他是个特别的小孩
And to him, you're his buddy, his best friend.
你是他最好的朋友
And when Andy plays with you, it's like even though you're not moving,
只要安弟跟你一起玩 路然你不会动
you feel like you're alive, because that's how he sees you.
你务党得自己是活的 因为他也认高你是真的
How did you know that?
人怎订知道 ?
Because Emily was just the same.
因为爱味莉也一样
She was my whole world.
她是我的一切
When somebody loved me
当我有人爱
Everything was beautiful
一切都美好
Every hour we spent together
每一分每一秒
Lives within my heart
都活在我心中
And when she was sad
每当她流泥
And when she was happy so was
每当她开心，我也很快乐
When she loved me
当她还爱我
Through the summer and the fall
不管寒冬或酷暑
We had each other That was all
只要有了彼此，我们不宁赛
Just she and I together
我跟她一起
Like it was meant to be
永速相假依
And when she was lonely
每当她孤踢
! was there to comfort her
我就陪著她
And I knew that
我也知道
So the years went by
一年一年遇去
l stayed the same
我还是一样
But she began to drift away
她印越走越速
! was left alone
和于下我一个
Still l waited for the day
但我仍然期待她
When she'd say
说一声
will always
我永速…
Love you
…都爱你
Lonely and forgotten
藉是我病主的等
! never thought she'd look my way
希望地再看一服
She smiled at me and held me
终僚她笑著抱著我
Just like she used to do
就像美好的从前
When somebody loved me
当我有人爱
Everything was beautiful
一切都美好
Every hour we spent together
每一分每一秒
Lives within my heart
都活在我心中
When she loved me
(爱心捐页)
You never forget kids like Emily or Andy.
我们忘不了爱味莉或安第
But they forget you.
但是他们会总了我们
- Jessie, I... 1 didn't know. - Just go.
以缘，我不知道 你走吧
How long will it last, Woody?
友情能维持多久?
Do you really think Andy is gonna take you to college
你真的以为安弟 会带你一起上大学
or on his honeymoon?
或是度密月吗 ?
Andy's growing up,
安弟会长大
and there's nothing you can do about it.
你和法阻止他
It's your choice, Woody.
你有了琴个选择
You can go back, or you can stay with us and last forever.
你可以回去 或是跟我们一起永速保存
You'll be adored by children for generations.
受到世世代代小孩的喜芝
Who am I to break up the Roundup gang?
我算哪根意，怎广能拆散 「 胡迪牛仔秀」 ?
- Hey, Woody, are you in here? - Nah. This one's empty too.
胡迪，你在吗 ? 这也是空盒子
- Woody! Woody! - Woody!
胡迪…
Pardon me, gentlemen, but have either of you seen a cowboy doll with a bad arm?
打摄了，请问雨位 有没有看到断手的牛仔 ?
- Why, no, I haven't. - Hey! He was talkin’ to me!
没有好 嘿，他在跟我讲话
- No! He was talkin’ to me! - Why, you...
他是在跟我讲话 可恶
You see, all along,
我们一直以禹
we thought the way into Zurg's fortress was through the main gate,
入口是札克城堡的大门
but in fact, the secret entrance is to the left, hidden in the shadows.
其赛秘密入口在堪尊 藏在险影底下
To the left in the shadows. Got it.
左遵的除影下，知道了
- Someone's coming. - Everyone, take cover.
有人来了 大家快找掩访
It was a big pile-up, but I don't want to bore you with the details.
路上大塞车，就看提了
Yes. Now, let me confirm your fax number.
请问你的传真又鄂 ?
- 011... - 011. Wait.
42.…-
That's a lot of numbers. No. I got it.
好多发码哦 知道了
- It's him. - The chicken man.
是他 公灯人
Funny, he doesn't look like poultry.
奇怪，他一点都不像家禽
That's the kidnapper, all right.
他就是乌菲没错
A kidnapper! An agent of Zurg if l ever saw one.
他才不是贿菲 他是札克的拟牙
And the piéce de résistance!
这就是我的乱价之实
I promise the collection will be the crown jewel of your museum.
我保证这会是 你最耀眼的收藏品
- It's Woody! - Now that I have your attention,
那是胡巡 这些货你都看了
imagine we added another zero to the price, huh?
我要在价色后面加一个零 什么 ?
- I'll pay anything you want. - Yes! Yes!
你要多少仅都行 粹采了
You got a deal! I'll be on the next flight to Japan!
咱们一言高定 我挫下一班机到日本
Quick. Into the poultry man's cargo unit.
快跳进家禽人的货舱
He'll lead us to Zurg. Move, move, move!
他会带我们找到札克 快…快…
Don't touch my moustache!
莎哟娜啦，再见唾
Rich, rich, rich, rich!
发了1发了!
Destroy Buzz Lightyear.
消减巴斯光年
- He didn't take the bag! - No time to lose!
他没拿走袋子 不能浪费时间
He's ascending in the vertical transporter.
他搭乘垂直输送机
All right, everyone. Hang on. We're gonna blast through the roof.
抓紧了，我们要街到屋顶
- Buzz? - To infinity and beyond!
巴斯 飞向宇密…浩瀚扰地
What are you? Insane? We're wasting time. Stand still, Godzilla.
你秀去啦 ? 别浪费时间 站好了，抱抱龙
I don't understand.
我搞不懂
Somehow my fuel cells have gone dry.
我的志铂怎广会没有志
Blast. He's on level 23.
错了，他到了23楼
How are we gonna get up there?
我们该怎广上去 ?
Maybe if we find some balloons, we could float to the top.
我们可以找八个气球溧上去
Are you kidding? Il say we stack ourselves up,
列开玩笑了 我们本如汉
push the intercom and pretend we're delivering a pizza.
再按对讲机 假扮我们在送比莽
How about a ham sandwich... with fries and a hot dog?
火腿三明治暮人条加热狗 怎广样 ?
What about me?
那我呢?
You can be the toy that comes with the meal.
你是随餐附赠玩具
Troops! Over here.
弟兄们，这多
Just like you said, lizard man. "In the shadows to the left."
大蜥蝎，跟你说的一样 入口在左关的险影下
OK. Let's move!
出动
Mission log. Have infiltrated enemy territory without detection
任务日读，我们海入逆区
and are making our way through the bowels of Zurg's fortress.
进入札克天王的城堡
You know, I think that Buzz aisle went to his head.
我看他是被冲氏了头
Oh, no. Which way do we go?
糟糙，往哪个方向?
- This way! - What makes you so sure?
这末 你怎订这广有把握?
I'm Buzz Lightyear. I'm always sure.
巴斯光年从不做没把握的事
We've been detected. The walls! They're closing in! Quick!
我们被发现了 处壁会把我们夹死
Help me prop up vegetable man, or we're done for.
马丛著快帮我揣一下
Hey! Put me down, you moron!
策蛋，快放我下来
Guys, look! It's not the walls! It's the elevator!
不是炉啦，是电梯
Come on. We've got no time to lose. Everyone, grab hold!
我们来不及了 大采儿，抓住我
What?
什么 ?
Buzz, why not just take the elevator?
巴斯 为什么不直接坐电梯 ?
They'll be expecting that.
这招会被他们料到
Hey, Buzz! Stop!
巴斯，等等
Slow down!
慢一点
To overnight six packages to Japan is how much?
六件隔天要送到日本的 快捷包庄要多少线 ?
- What? That's in yen, right? - No, dollars, sir.
什么?是日赔吧?
- Dollars? - Yes.
美元 ?
You are deliberately taking advantage of people in a hurry, you know that?
我在超时间 你们是故意抢袋耶
All right. I'll do it! All right. Fine.
好啦…好吧
I'll have the stuff in the lobby, and you'd better be here in 15 minutes,
我会在大廉等 你们最好十五分甸和后到
because I have a plane to catch, do you hear me?
我要赶赤机，取到吗?
We're finally going. Can you believe it?
我们终於要走了 你相信吗 ?
That's custom-fitted foam insulation you'll be riding in, Bullseye.
那是特别订做的箱子
First class all the way!
这一趟要坐头等舱
You know what? I'm actually excited about this.
老实说，我觉得很兴奋
l mean it. I really am!
我是说真的
And why shouldn't you be?
那是当然了
Swing your partner do-si-do
跟著舞伴左掏右晃
- Look at you, dancing cowboy! - Look! I'm doin’ the box step!
你是个跳舞的牛仔 瞧，我在跳方浙矣耶
Hey, heads up down there!
下面小心
- Pork bellies are fallin’. - Hey, how much farther, Buzz?
和猪肚掉下来了 还 有多速呀 ?
Halfway there.
就快到了
My arms can't hold on much longer!
我的手撑不下去了
Too... heavy.
太重了
What was I thinking?
我真傻
My antigravity servos!
我有反重力功能
Hang tight, everyone. I'm going to let go of the wall.
抓紧了，我要放手了
- What? - He wouldn't.
什么 ? 他不会吧
- One... - He would.
-一 他会
Two...
别放手…
Three!
三
To infinity and beyond!
飞向宇密…浩瀚扰地
Approaching destination. Reengaging gravity.
接近目标，人恢复重力
Area secure.
安全
It's OK, troops.
没事了
The antigravity sickness will wear off momentarily. Now let's move!
友重力引起的党骇 马上就会消失，前进吧
Remind me to glue his helmet shut when we get back.
记得提醒我回去以后 要好好教训他一顿
How ‘bout givin' me a little intro there, Jessie?
翌尹，介绍我出场吧
Introducing the high-ridin'-est cowboy around...
我要介绍 西部最棒最酷的牛仔
You forgot "rootin'-tootin'-est"!
妃了说最炫
The high-ridin'-est, rootin'-tootin'-est cowboy hero of all time,
西部最棒最酷 最炫的牛仔英雄
Sheriff Woody!
胡迪整长
Say, little missy, you notice any trouble around these parts?
嘿，小妞，这鬼有麻烦吗 ?
Nary a bit, not with Sheriff Woody around.
没有，胡迪警长会搞定一切
Wait-wait-wait! got it! This is great! OK!
等等，我有了
The bandits got the critters tied up in the burning barn. Now the best part!
强盗把小动物 天在著火的毅念
Help us! The barn's on fire!
救命呀，骨分著火了
I've got ya, critters. No need to worry.
我来了，别害怕
Woody saves the day again!
胡迪又解除了危机
I have to ride off into the sunset...
我得潇瀑的骑向落日
Ride like the wind, Bullseye!
快马加葛吧，红心
Watch it. Wait. I'm ticklish, OK?
列这榜，我怕半
Oh, you are?
是吗?
No, no, no. Cut it out. Stop it. Stop it.
住手，列放样
No, please. No, no. Stop! Stop!
快住手，住手
Mission log. Have reached Zurg's command deck,
任务日试 这是杞克的指挥舱
but no sign of him or his wooden captive.
没有他和木头俘钼的跳影
- Please, no! - That's Woody!
那是胡巡
Please, please, no!
拜旗，住手
Buzz, can you see? What's going on?
你看得到吗 ? 怎广回事 ?
- Take that! - To the left.
左遵
No, your left.
你的寺中啦
- Take it up higher. - What's happening?
高一点 怎广回事 ?
It's horrible. They're torturing him.
太可怕了，他们在拷问他
- What are we gonna do, Buzz? - Use your head!
我们该怎广办 ? 用用你的脑袋
But I don't wanna use my head!
但是我不想要用我的脑袋
What's going on here?
这是怎广回事 ?
Buzz, guys! Hey, how did you find me?
巴斯，大彩儿 你们怎庆找得到我 ?
Watch yourself!
小心是
We're here to spring ya, Woody!
我们来救你了
You heard of kung fu?
职过扰影腿吗 ?
Well, get ready for pork chop.
党党我的火腿
Prepare to meet Mr. Angry Eyes!
见识我愤怒侯眼的威力
Hold it, now! Hey, you don't understand! These are my friends!
等等，你们搞错了 他们是我的朋友
- Yeah, we're his friends! - No, Rex, mean they're my friends!
没错，我们是他的朋友 不是啦，我是说他们
Hey, stop it! You leave him alone, springy dog!
站住，策狗，给我放开他
- Grab Woody, and let's go! - Fellas, hold it!
快去救胡巡
- Buzz, put me down! - Quick! To the vent!
巴斯，放我下来 撤退，生到通风孔
- They're stealing him! - No!
他被抢走了
Hold it right there!
大彩儿列动
- Buzz? - You again?
巴斯 又是你
Woody! Thank goodness you're all right.
胡迪，幸好你没事
Buzz, what is going on?
这是怎广回事 ?
Hold on. lam Buzz Lightyear, and I'm in charge of this detachment.
慢著，我是巴斯光年 这和里由我指挥
No, I'm Buzz Lightyear.
我才是巴斯光年
- I'm Buzz Lightyear!
我是巴斯光年 我才是
So, who's the real Buzz?
谁是真的巴斯?
- lam!
我是
Don't let this impostor fool you!
列上这个冒牌货的当
He's been trained by Zurg himself to mimic my every move.
杞克训练他模仿 我的一举一动
Buzz!
巴斯
l had a feelin’ it was you.
我就知道是你
My front end just had to catch up with my back end.
只是我有时候头尾不分
Will somebody please explain what's going on?
请你们解释好吗 ?
It's all right, space ranger. It's a code 546.
没事了，太空战警 这是546密令
- You mean it's a... - Yes.
你是说… 没错
- And he's a... - Oh, yeah.
是的
Your Majesty.
陛下
Woody, you're in danger here. We need to leave now.
胡迪，你有危险，快走吧
Al's selling you toa museum in Japan!
艾霄要把你走到 日本的博物馆
I know. It's OK, Buzz. l actually wanna go.
我知道，没关你
- What? - Are you crazy?
什么 ? 你疯啦 ?
Look, the thing is, I'm a rare Sheriff Woody doll,
我是稀有的胡迪警长玩偶
and these guys are my Roundup gang.
他们是我的牛仔表彩伴
- What are you talking about? - Woody's Roundup!
你在说什么呀? 胡迪牛仔秀
It's this great old TV show, and I was the star. See? Now look.
我是一个电视节目的明星
Look! Look at me! See? That's me!
你看，你们看，那是我耶
- This is weirdin' me out. - Buzz, it was a national phenomenon.
我受不了了 我曾经可动一时
There was all this merchandise that got packed up. You should have seen it.
我逮有一大堆过遵商品 你们应该瞧瞧
There was a record player and a yo-yo. Buzz, I was a yo-yo!
唱机、溜溜球 我曾经是溜溜球耶
- "Was"? - Stop this nonsense and let's go.
曾经? 列说傻话了，咱们走吧
Buzz.
巴斯
I can't go. I can't abandon these guys.
我不能于下这些朋友
They need me to get into this museum.
他们需要我才能进博物馆
Without me, they'll go back into storage. Maybe forever!
否则他们就得回去甸藏室 永速被关起来
Woody, you're not a collector's item. You're a child's plaything.
你不是收藏品 你是给小孩玩的
You are a toy!
你是个玩具
For how much longer? One more rip, and Andy's done with me.
我还能撑多久 ? 我再被扯破安弟就会抛素我
And what do I do then, Buzz? Huh? You tell me.
到时候我该怎广办 ? 你倒是说啊
Somewhere in that pad of stuffing is a toy who taught me
我记得你曾经告诉我
that life's only worth living if you're bein’ loved by a kid.
当有小孩爱你时 生命才有价值
And I traveled all this way to rescue that toy
我大老速跑来救你
because I believed him.
因为我相信你的证
Well, you wasted your time.
你白跑一趟了
- Let's go, everyone. - What about Woody?
走吧，大彩儿 胡迪呢?
He's not coming with us.
他不跟来了
But... But Andy's coming home tonight.
今晚安弟要回家耶
Then we'd better make sure we're there waiting for him.
那我们最好超回去等他
I don't have a choice, Buzz. This is my only chance.
我别乱还择 这是我唯一的机会
To do what, Woody? Watch kids from behind glass and never be loved again?
什么机会?永速隔著玻璃 看著小孩玩吐?
Some life.
真可翡
- ls everybody OK? - Sheriff Woody!
大家都没事吧 ? 胡迪整长
- 1 knew you'd make it! - Now, remember, deputies,
你救了我们 记住了，小朋友
the real treasures are your friends and family.
家人和朋友才是你们的一切
Before I go, kids, 1 want to share somethin’ special with you,
我在走之前 想要跟你们分享这首歌
- for the times I'm not around. - Good going, Woody!
太好了
I thought they'd never leave.
终於所脱他们了
You've got a friend in me
我是你好朋友
- Woody? - You've got troubles
胡迪 如果你有麻烦
Well, I've got ‘em too
我会来帮忙
There isn't anything ! wouldn't do for you
我顾篇你赴混蹈火
We stick together and see it through
只要团结就能解决
‘Cause you've got a friend in me
因为我是你好朋友
Some other folks might be a little bit smarter than 1am
也许别人比我隐明一点
Bigger and stronger too
也比我高大比我强
Maybe
也许吧
But none of them will ever love you
但是从来没有人
The way I do
像我这广爱你
It's me and you, boy
我们是好朋友
And as the years go by
一年一年遇去
Our friendship will never die
我们的友谊更加坚固
- What am I doing? - You're gonna see it's our destiny
我这是在干嘛?
- Buzz! Wait! Wait! - Woody, where are you going?
巴斯，等等我 你要去哪里 ?
You're right, Prospector. I can't stop Andy from growing up.
你说得对，安弟一定会长大
But I wouldn't miss it for the world.
但是我不想错遇每一刻
- No! - Buzz!
不 ! 巴斯
- Yes?
干乌?
I'm coming with you!
我要跟你们走
Wait... wait... wait. I'll be back in just a second.
等一下，我马上回来
Way to go, cowboy!
干得好，牛仔
- Hey, you guys... Come with me. - What?
大颗儿，跟我一起来吧 什么 ?
Andy will play with all of us. I know it!
安弟会跟我们一起玩
Woody, I... 1... I don't know. I...
胡迪，我不晓得耶
Wouldn't you give anything just to have one more day with Emily?
难道你不想再陪伴爱味莉吗 ?
Come on, Jessie. This is what it's all about: to make a child happy.
翌尹，最重要的是 让一个小孩快乐
And you know it. Bullseye, are you with me?
人心里很明白 红心，你来不来 ?
Prospector, how ‘bout you?
老矿工，你说呢 ?
- Prospector? - You're outta your box!
老矿工? 你获并盒子了
I tried reasoning with you, Woody,
我试著跟你讲道理
but you keep forcing me to take extreme measures.
但是你逼得我不择手段
Wait a minute. You turned on the TV last night, not Jessie.
昨晚是你打开电视 不是浴缘
Look, we have an eternity to spend together in the museum.
我们要永中一起留在博物馆
Let's not start off by pointing fingers, shall we?
你不要破壤咱们之间的感情
You really are Stinky Pete, aren't you?
你真的很可恶耶
Prospector, this isn't fair.
老矿工，这样很不公平
"Fair"? I'll tell you what's not fair.
不公平 ? 什和码叫不公平 ?
Spending a lifetime on a dime-store shelf watching every other toy be sold.
我一草子都坐在架子上 看著别的玩具被买走
Well, finally my waiting has paid off,
现在我终尖效出头
and no hand-me-down cowboy doll is gonna mess it up for me now!
一个臭牛仓 休想玉了我的好事
Buzz. Help, Buzz! Guys!
巴斯 救命呀，巴斯
It's too late, Woody. That silly Buzz Lightweight can't help you.
太膛了 那个撒隆巴斯划不了你
His name is Buzz Lightyear.
他的名字是巴斯光年
Whatever. I've always hated those upstart space toys.
随便啦 我最讨屡太空玩具了
It's stuck! What do we do?
卡住了，怎广办 ?
Should I use my head?
要用我脑代咀?
It's Al!
是区埃
Look at the time. I'm gonna be late!
我快赶不及了
Figures. I can't miss this flight! I've gotta pack.
我不能错过班机，我得打包
All right. Let's see. Wallet, keys, tickets,
袋包、锭是、机票
passport, beef jerky, very expensive over there.
护照、牛肉乾…在日本很贵
Shower! Il can skip the shower.
洗深 来不及洗了
I just gotta get outta here now!
我得走了
Quick! To the elevator!
快去坐电梯
Hurry. Il can hear it coming.
快点，志梯来了
So, we meet again, Buzz Lightyear,
巴斯光年，我们又见面了
for the last time.
这坎你死定了
It's Zurg! Watch out! He's got an ion blaster!
是杞克天王 小心，他有郊子克
Quick! Get on!
快上电梯
The emergency hatch! Come on!
紧急逃生口，快点
- Come on! Hurry! - But Buzz is in peril!
来吧，快点 巴斯有危险耶
Buzz.., Buzz... Buzz.., Lightyear to the rescue!
巴斯光年…择救世界
Surrender, Buzz Lightyear. l have won.
投降吧，巴斯光年，我赢了
I'll never give in. You killed my father!
我不会投降，你灯了我父亲
No, Buzz. lam your father.
不，巴斯，我就是你父亲
Come on! Come on! Come on!
快点…快点…
Buzz, you could have defeated Zurg all along!
巴斯，你可以打败札克
You just need to believe in yourself!
你只要相信自己
- Prepare to die! - L can't look!
领匹吧 我不敢看
I did it. I finally defeated Zurg!
我成功了 我终於打败札克了
Father.
和爸和爸
Finally!
终蕉到了
How are we gonna get him now?
我们该怎广救他 ?
Pizza, anyone?
谁要吃比荐 ?
- Go, go, go! - [got it!
快走，快走 我接到了
Buzz, are you coming?
巴斯，你来不来 ?
No, I have a lot of catching up to do with my dad.
不了，我要多队陪我爸各
Good throw, son. That's my boy. Go long, Buzzy!
生得好，乖儿子 跑速一点，小巴斯
- You're a great dad. - Farewell.
你是个好和苞和，莲功 再见了
Does anyone know how to drive?
有人会开车吗 ?
Slink, take the pedals. Rex, you navigate.
弹簧狗，踩油门 抱抱龙，看方向
Hamm and Potato, operate the levers and knobs.
火腿和和蛋头，控制按键
- Strangers. - From the outside.
陌生人 外面来的
- Oh, no. - He's at a red light! We can catch him!
惨了 是红灯，快追上去
Maximum power, Slink!
弹簧狗，全速前进
It turned green! Hurry!
录炮了，快点
- Why won't it go? - Use the Wand of Power.
为什么不动 ? 你们要用动力棍
- Rex, which way? - Left! No, no! l mean right!
抱抱龙，往哪儿 ? 左，我是说右
That's right! No, mean left! Left is right!
对了，左天才对
Buzz, he's turning left! He's turning left!
巴斯，他左转了
Oh, boy!
天啊
I seriously doubt he's gettin’ this kind of mileage.
这辆车吃油吃得很鬼
Go right! To the right! Right-right-right-right!
右塌 !右夸!
You have saved our lives. We are eternally grateful.
你救了我们 我们永吉感计你
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Whatever.
好啦，随便啦
The white zone is for immediate loading and unloading...
白线只准务货或上下和磁客
No parking.
不准停车
Guys, we can't park here! It's a white zone!
不能停这儿，这是白禾
You have saved our lives. We are eternally grateful.
你救了我们 我们永吉感计你
- Final boarding call... - There he is!
他在那儿
. for Far East Airlines flight 451 to Tokyo.
前往束京的班机马上起习
All confirmed passengers must board at this time.
已登记的旅客请马上和悚机
Passenger Twitch, passenger Leon Twitch, please pick up...
旅客托维奇 请和地勤人员联络…
You have saved our lives. We are eternally grateful.
你救了我们 我们永吉感计你
- Will you leave me alone? - Someone's coming!
别绰著我，好吐? 有人来了
- A puppy! - Bark-bark-bark-bark.
小狗狗
Bark-bark-bark-bark-bark.
汪汪汪…
Listen, flyboy.
给我职好，小飞仔
The contents of that case are worth more than you make in a year!
箱子里的东西你赔不起
- You got that? You be careful! - l understand, sir.
上不上螃 ? 我明白
Do you have a "fragile" sticker or something?
给我小心点 没有上易碎」 的标答吗 ?
l had a box of cookies once that came back as crumbs!
我带明一盒饼喜 钻果沟成饼赦羽
The Mystic Portal!
神奇的入口
Once we go through, we just need to find that case.
我们进去和后 只要找到箱子就行了
Buzz, my back end's goin' to Baton Rouge!
巴斯 我的尾巴要往德州去了
Slinky!
弹筑狗
Here we come, Woody! Woody, here we come! Woody!
胡迪，我们来了 胡迪
Nice flash though.
好炫的闪光灯
OK, Woody, let's go!
胡迪，走吧
Take that, space toy.
吃我一源，太空玩具
Hey! No one does that to my friend!
你不能打我的朋友
Your choice, Woody.
我警告你
You can go to Japan together or in pieces.
你再不乎乎合作 我就把你拆了
If he fixed ya once, he can fix ya again. Now get in the box!
他一样能把你补好 给我进去
- Never! - Fine!
不要 好吧
- No! - Gotcha!
还到你了
Idiots! Children destroy toys!
白遍，小孩子会毁了玩具
You'll all be ruined, forgotten!
你们会被玩壤、遗忘
Spending eternity rotting in some landfill!
永下被埋在这圾场
Well, Stinky Pete, I think it's time you learned the true meaning of playtime.
遵遇彼得 你该学会怎广跟小孩玩了
- Right over there, guys! - No. No! No!
把他放到那儿 不!不!
Atlantic Air flight 810 from Point Richmond
大西洋航空810训班机
now arriving at Gate 3.
抵达三咏登机门
Look, Barbie. A big ugly man doll.
芭比，你看，好梗的老娃娃
He needs a makeover.
我要玫他整容
Hi! You'll like Amy.
嗨，你会喜欢艾美
She's an artist!
她是天才艺本家
Come on, hon!
走吧，乖竺
Happy trails, Prospector.
祝你幸福，老态工
- Buzz! Woody! - Help us out here!
巴斯、胡地 者帮忙
- Oh, no. Jessie! Come on! - Woody!
烧了，昱尹，快点 救命啊
Jessie!
翌多
Come on, Buzz.
巴斯，上来吧
Ride like the wind, Bullseye!
快马加葛吧，红心
Come on, Bullseye!
跑快凤，红心
Buzz, give me a boost!
巴斯，把我抬起来
Woody!
胡迪
Here's the rest!
只剩下人这些了
Excuse me, ma'am, but believe you're on the wrong flight.
抱娄，小姐，人搭错班机了
- Woody! - Come on, Jess.
胡迪 来吧，翌缘
It's time to take you home.
我带你回家
- But what if Andy doesn't like me? - Nonsense! Andy'll love you!
要是安弟不喜数我怎订办 ? 列傻了，他会喜数人
- Besides, he's got a little sister. - He does?
而且他有个小妹妹 真的吗 ?
Why didn't you say so? Let's go!
你怎麻不早说 ? 快走吧
Hold it! There's a couple more bags coming from the terminal!
等等，迁有疲件行李没到
OK. On three.
我数到三
- One, two... - Too late!
-一    - 太膛了
Put 'em on the next flight!
等下一班机吧
- This is bad. - How are we gonna get outta here?
这下可糟了 我们该怎麻出去 ?
Over there! Come on!
这儿，来吧
- You sure about this? - No! Let's go!
你确定吗 ? 不1来吧 !
Hold on, Woody!
抓系了，胡过
- What's a cowboy without his hat? - Buzz!
牛仔没有牛仔赐怎广行 ? 巴斯
Buzz! Buzz, get behind the tires!
巴斯，到输胎后面
Jessie, let go of the plane!
弹尹，放手
What? Are you crazy?
你疯啦 ?
Just pretend it's the final episode of Woody's Roundup.
假装这是 「 胡迪牛仔秀」 大结局
But it was canceled! We never saw if you made it!
它被停播了，你不知道结局
Well, then, let's find out together!
我们现在一起演吧
We did it! We did it! We did it!
成功了 ! 成功了!
Nice ropin', cowboy.
干得好，牛仔
That was definitely Woody's finest hour!
这是胡迪最光荣的一刻
Your hat, partner.
你的帽子，伙伴
Let's... go home.
咱们回家吧
Hey, Woody! Woody?
胡迪，胡迪 ?
Wow! New toys!
新玩具，酷鉴了
Cool! Thanks, Mom!
谢了，妈咪
It's Bazooka Jane and her jet-propelled horse!
火稍炮珍妮和她的喷射马
Woody, Buzz, that polecat Zurg has stolen my space cows
胡迪、巴斯 札克偷走我的太空牛
and they're headed for the asteroid!
他们未到陨石带了
Andy, come on, hon. Time to go.
安弟，该走了
- Hey, you fixed Woody! - Yeah.
你把胡迪补好了 是啊
Glad I decided not to take him to camp. His whole arm might have come off.
幸好我没带他去牛仔警 要不然他整售手都会被扯断
Well, what do you know?
真没想到
Bullseye, we're part of a family again!
红心，我们又有新的家了
Ma'am, I...
小姐，我想告诉你
l wanted to say you're a bright young woman
你是个毛线组饮的…
with a beautiful "yarnful" of hair.
…漂亮姑娘
"Hairful" of yarn. It's...
我是说秀要组逸
I must go.
我得走了
Well, aren't you the sweetest space toy I ever met?
你是我见明 最可爱的太空玩具
What's that? Bark-bark?
什么事 ?
This fella says he needs to go out for a little private time.
小狗狗得到和后院方便一下
That critter needs help!
那焦狗需要旭忙
Rex, I could use a hand over here, buddy.
抱抱龙，加间忙
I don't need to play. I've lived it!
我不必玩了 我亲手打败通札克
Oh, nuts!
惨了惨了，可恶
Welcome to Al's Toy Barn.
欢迎光了覆葡霄玩具城
We've got the lowest prices in town.
我们的价格最便宜
Everything for a buck-buck-buck.
每赚玩具都一老角
Well, l guess crime doesn't pay.
犯罪没有好下场
Andy did a great job, huh? Nice and strong!
安弟把我颖得好结实
I like it. Makes you look... tough.
我喜欢，你很强则
You have saved our lives. We are eternally grateful.
你救了我们 我们永吉感计你
You saved their lives? My hero!
你救了他们 ? 吗，我的英雄
And they're so adorable! Let's adopt them!
他们好可爱 我们领闵他们吧
Daddy!
和爸和爸
Oh, no.
不要吧
Wheezy, you're fixed!
咏咏，你被修好了
Oh, yeah. Mr. Shark looked in the toy box and found me an extra squeaker.
是啊 溜急先生找到一个号咏盒
- And... how do you feel? - l feel swell.
你觉得怎榜 ? 好得不得了
In fact, I think I feel a song comin’ on.
我想要鸭大家卖唱一曲
You've got a friend in me
我是你好朋友
You just remember what your old pal said
紧紧记住这名话
Come on over. You are such a big girl.
妹妹，越长越高唾
Andy, you think she's ready to drive the car yet?
你看她可以并车了吐?
Yeah, and I can teach her.
可以啊，我来教好
- You still worried? - About Andy?
你膛在担心? 担心安弟 ?
- No, it'll be fun while it lasts. - I'm proud of you, cowboy.
才不，好时光要珍惜 我以你禹傲，牛仔
Besides, when it all ends, I'll have old Buzz Lightyear to keep me company...
就算安弟长大了 巴斯光年还是我的好朋友
..for infinity and beyond.
一同飞向宇密…直到永速
You're gonna see it's our destiny
这是上天广定的命到
- You've got a friend in me - Yes, you do
我是你好朋友 一点也没错
- That's the truth
说得好
You've got a friend
我是你…
In me
…好朋友
Yeah!
好耶